rdserviceonline.com 2019-02-09

# Privacy Policy – Register IDEMIA (Morpho) fingerprint biometric sensor with UIDAI

**PRIVACY POLICY**

This privacy policy ( **“Privacy Policy”** ) sets forth the policy of Smartchip Pvt. Ltd, a company registered under the Companies Act, 2013, (Company) and having its head office at D-216 Sector 63, Noida 201301 ( **“Company** **”, “we”, “us”** and/or **“our”** ), with regard to the collection, usage and protection of personal data or information that the users (“ **you** ”, “ **your** ”) may provide to us while using the website [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/)( **“Website”** ) and through other related services.

This Privacy Policy is an electronic record in the form of an electronic contract formed under the Information Technology Act, 2000 and the rules made thereunder and the amended provisions pertaining to electronic documents/records in various statutes as amended by the Information Technology Act, 2000. This Privacy Policy does not require any physical, electronic or digital signature.

This Privacy Policy shall be read together with the terms of use or other terms and conditions/policies of the Company.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using our Application or Website.

By using our Application or Website, you are accepting the terms described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Website or Application.

Your use of the Website and services and tools are governed by the following terms and conditions (“Terms of Use”) as applicable to the Website including the applicable policies which are incorporated herein by way of reference. If you transact on the Website, You shall be subject to the policies that are applicable to the Website for such transaction. By mere use of the Website, You shall be contracting with Smart chip Private Limited and these terms and conditions including the policies constitute your binding obligations, with rdserviceonline.

For the purpose of these terms wherever the context so requires "You" or “User” shall mean any natural or legal person who has agreed to become a buyer on the Website by providing Registration Data while registering on the Website as Registered User using the computer systems. rdserviceonline.com allows the User to surf the Website or making purchases after registering on the Website. The term “We”, “Us”, “Our” shall mean www.rdserviceonline.com (Smart chip Private Limited)

When you use any of the services provided by us through the Website, including but not limited to, you will be subject to the rules, guidelines, policies, terms, and conditions applicable to such service, and they shall be deemed to be incorporated into this Privacy Policy and shall be considered as part and parcel of this Policy. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy, at any time without any prior written notice to you. It is your responsibility to review this Policy periodically for updates / changes. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes will mean that you accept and agree to the revisions. As long as you comply with this Policy, We grant you a personal, non-exclusive, non-transferable, limited privilege to enter and use the Website.

**YOUR ACCOUNT AND REGISTRATION OBLIGATIONS**

If you use the Website [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/), you shall be responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Display Name and Password and you shall be responsible for all activities that occur under your Display Name and Password. You agree that if You provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete or We have reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or not in accordance with the this Terms of Use, We shall have the right to indefinitely suspend or terminate or block access of your membership on the Website and refuse to provide You with access to the Website.

**WHAT INFORMATION OR DATA IS COLLECTED FROM YOU AND HOW WE USE IT?**

When you visit [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/) website, we may collect information regarding the domain name and host from which you are accessing the website, the internet protocol address of the computer / laptop or internet service provider you   are using and any other statistical data. The users/ customers are informed through this privacy policy that [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/) uses cookies and tracking technology for website and mobile site users depending on the features offered. Personal information will not be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personal identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/) also request its users/customers to go through the Cookies as mentioned below in this Policy.

**REGISTRATION**

If you choose to become a registered member/user/customer of rdserviceonline.com, you must provide us with your name, mobile number, e-mail address etc. Mobile number and e-mail would be verified using OTP.  This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons

  1. Personal Identification- to keep information of user to keep trace on RD-registered device service.
  2. To purchase RD- registered device service offered by rdserviceonline.com on the website.
  3. To allow us to contact you for customer services, if necessary.

**PROCEDURE FOR COLLECTION OF INFORMATION AND ITS USE**

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this website [rdserviceonline.com](https://shop.havells.com/). We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily provide us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell, access or rent this information to anyone.

We will use the information provided by you to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, unless required by government or statutory authority or regulatory offices under the law.

**PURCHASING**

In order to purchase through our website you must provide us with certain Personal Information such as your name, mobile number and e - mail address. You can make payment through different options like Credit Card, Debit Card, and Net Banking in a secured environment. Payment gateway require this information to process, fulfill and confirm your order and transactions and keep you informed of each transaction's status.

**SECURITY**

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever payment gateway obtain sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to payment gateway in a secured way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page.

We want you to feel confident using our Application/Website. However, no system can be completely secure. Although we implement security measures designed to protect your personal information from unauthorized access and while we use reasonable efforts to protect your personal information we cannot guarantee its absolute security and you should not expect that your information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure. We recommend that you should also take care with how you handle and disclose your information and should avoid sending your information through insecure email.

We are committed to ensuring that your personal data or information is secure. We take appropriate security measures (including physical, electronic and procedural measures) to help safeguard your personal data or information from unauthorized access and disclosure. We use encryption in the transmission of your personal information between your system and ours and we use firewalls to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your information.

**WITH WHOM YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IS SHARED?**

When you do purchase from the website, we shall provide certain mobile number and e-mail of yours to the SMS/ E-mail gateway or other third party who are also involved in order to successfully fulfill.

For the above purpose [rdserviceonline.com](https://shop.havells.com/) ensures you that the information provided to the SMS/ E-mail gateway will not be divulged or diverted to any third parties other than as required by the government agencies / authorities, statutory bodies and any other institutions that are authorized.

However, we do not sell or rent individual customer names or other Personal Information to third parties except with the entities with whom we have alliance for providing the services.

**OTHER SITUATIONS:**

We also may disclose your information:

In response to a court order or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us in our sole discretion.

when disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, report or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of us, our users, our employees or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our website terms and conditions or other agreements or policies.

In connection with a substantial corporate transaction such as the sale of our business, a merger, consolidation, or asset sale or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**HOW YOU CAN OPT-OUT OF RECEIVING OUR PROMOTIONAL E-MAILS**

At any time, you may unsubscribe from our newsletter or promotional services by writing to [unsubscribe@rdserviceonline.com](mailto:unsubscribe@rdserviceonline.com). You will occasionally receive email updates from us about fare sales in [www.rdserviceonline.com](http://www.rdserviceonline.com/), special offers, new [rdserviceonline.com](https://shop.havells.com/) services and products, and other noteworthy items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative.

If you wish not to receive them, please click on the ‘unsubscribe’ link or follow the instructions in each email message or send us an email [unsubscribe@rdserviceonline.com](mailto:unsubscribe@rdserviceonline.com)

**COOKIES:**

In an effort to improve the quality of our Application/Website, we analyze information provided to us by your device when you view or use the Application/Website, such as the applications you came from, the type of browser you use, the device from which you connected to the Application, the time and date of access, and other information that does not personally identify you.

We analyze this information using cookies or small text files which include an anonymous unique identifier to enhance your experience. Cookies are sent to a user’s browser from our servers and are stored on the user’s device for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. Sending a cookie to a user’s browser enables us to collect information about that user and keep a record of the user’s preferences when using our Application or Website. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you use our Application or Website. A session cookie enables certain features of the Application/Website and is deleted from your computer/mobile/device when you disconnect from or leave the Application/Website. A persistent cookie remains after you close the Application/Website and may be used by your device on subsequent visits. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the Website/Application.

**ACCESS TO OTHER MEDIA**

You can choose to access certain third party social media applications and services through our Website/Application. When you do so, you are sharing information with these Other Social Media, and the information you share will be governed by their privacy policies and terms of service. You may also be able to modify your privacy settings with these Other Social Media, for example, control what information the Other Social Media disclose to third party services like us. When you add Other Social Media accounts when you use our services or sign into our Website/Application using your Other Social Media account, we will collect relevant information necessary to enable our Website/Application to access that Other Social Media, but you will provide your sign in information, like your password, directly to such Other Social Media (and not to us). As part of such integration, the Other Social Media will provide us with access to certain information that you have provided to such Other Social Media, and we may use, store and disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and, if and to the extent applicable, the policies of such Other Social Media Service. In addition, we may provide certain information about you or your activities of using our services, or that you have otherwise provided to us, to such Other Social Media Service as part of such integration (including information that may be used by such Other Social Media to personalize ads for you). However, please remember that the manner in which Other Social Media use, store and disclose your information is governed by the policies of such third parties, and we shall have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any Other Social Media that may be enabled on our Website/Application.

**THIRD PARTY WEBSITES**

This Privacy Policy does not address and we are not responsible for the privacy, information or other practices of any third party, any third-party service providers and any other third party operating any software application or website.

There may be a number of links on our Website or our Application where you may click on a link to access other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy. For example, if you click on an advertisement or a search result on our Website or Application, you may be taken to a website that we do not control. These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you and, in some instances, provide us with information about your activities on those websites. We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the “privacy” link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

**ACCOUNT SECURITY**

Your account is protected by your account password and we urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe by not disclosing your password and by logging out of your account after each use. You are solely responsible for the confidentiality of any password and other account information that you create in order to access or use our Website/ Application. You agree to notify us immediately of any unauthorized use of your account, username or password. You also agree that the Company is not liable in any manner for any loss that you may incur as a result of any third party using your password, either with or without your knowledge. You are solely liable for any losses incurred by us, our affiliates, officers, directors, employees, consultants, agents, and representatives due to misuse of your account or password. You will not under any circumstances use the account, username or password of someone else at any time.

**SUBMISSION OF FINANCIAL INFORMATION**

You agree, understand and confirm that the financial information such as bank account/debit/credit card or other payment instrument details provided by you for using our services through our Website/Application will be correct and accurate and you shall not use the bank account/debit/credit card or other payment instrument which is not lawfully owned and/or authorized to be used by you. You further agree and undertake to provide the correct and valid financial information to us.

**GOVERNING LAW**

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of India and the courts in Noida shall have the exclusive jurisdiction.

**GRIEVANCE OFFICER**

The contact detail of the Grievance Officer is provided below:

E-mail address: **[**[support@rdserviceonline.com](mailto:support@rdserviceonline.com) **]**

**CONCERNS AND QUERIES**

If you have any concerns or comments about this Privacy Policy or our use of your personally identifiable information, please contact us at 1800 419 0328.
